（空气呼啸）
(air whooshing)
- 什么是迁移学习？
- What is transfer learning?
迁移学习的思想
The idea of transfer learning
是利用所获得的知识
is to leverage the knowledge acquired
通过在另一项任务上使用大量数据训练的模型。
by a model trained with lots of data on another task.
模型 A 将专门针对任务 A 进行训练。
The model A will be trained specifically for task A.
现在假设你想训练模型 B
Now let's say you want to train a model B
为了不同的任务。
for a different task.
一种选择是从头开始训练模型。
One option would be to train the model from scratch.
这可能需要大量的计算、时间和数据。
This could take lots of computation, time and data.
相反，我们可以初始化模型 B
Instead, we could initialize model B
与模型 A 具有相同的权重，
with the same weights as model A,
将模型 A 的知识转移到任务 B 上。
transferring the knowledge of model A on task B.
从头开始训练时，
When training from scratch,
所有模型的权重都是随机初始化的。
all the model's weight are initialized randomly.
在这个例子中，我们正在训练一个 BERT 模型
In this example, we are training a BERT model
在识别任务上
on the task of recognizing
两个句子是否相似。
if two sentences are similar or not.
在左边，它是从头开始训练的，
On the left, it's trained from scratch,
在右侧，它正在微调预训练模型。
and on the right it's fine-tuning a pretrained model.
正如我们所见，使用迁移学习
As we can see, using transfer learning
并且预训练模型产生了更好的结果。
and the pretrained model yields better results.
如果我们训练更长时间也没关系。
And it doesn't matter if we train longer.
从头开始的训练准确率上限在 70% 左右
The training from scratch is capped around 70% accuracy
而预训练模型轻松击败了 86%。
while the pretrained model beats the 86% easily.
这是因为预训练模型
This is because pretrained models
通常接受大量数据的训练
are usually trained on large amounts of data
为模型提供统计理解
that provide the model with a statistical understanding
预训练期间使用的语言。
of the language used during pretraining.
在计算机视觉中，
In computer vision,
迁移学习已成功应用
transfer learning has been applied successfully
将近十年。
for almost ten years.
模型经常在 ImageNet 上进行预训练，
Models are frequently pretrained on ImageNet,
包含 120 万张照片图像的数据集。
a dataset containing 1.2 millions of photo images.
每个图像都按 1000 个标签中的一个进行分类。
Each image is classified by one of 1000 labels.
像这样在标记数据上训练
Training like this, on labeled data
称为监督学习。
is called supervised learning.
在自然语言处理中，
In Natural Language Processing,
迁移学习是最近才出现的。
transfer learning is a bit more recent.
与 ImageNet 的一个关键区别是预训练
A key difference with ImageNet is that the pretraining
通常是自我监督的，
is usually self-supervised,
这意味着它不需要人工注释
which means it doesn't require humans annotations
对于标签。
for the labels.
一个非常常见的预训练目标
A very common pretraining objective
是猜测句子中的下一个单词。
is to guess the next word in a sentence.
这只需要大量的文本。
Which only requires lots and lots of text.
例如 GPT-2，就是这样预训练的
GPT-2 for instance, was pretrained this way
使用 4500 万个链接的内容
using the content of 45 millions links
用户在 Reddit 上发布。
posted by users on Reddit.
自监督预训练目标的另一个例子
Another example of self-supervised pretraining objective
是预测随机屏蔽词的值。
is to predict the value of randomly masked words.
这类似于填空测试
Which is similar to fill-in-the-blank tests
你可能在学校做过。
you may have done in school.
BERT 是使用英文维基百科以这种方式进行预训练的
BERT was pretrained this way using the English Wikipedia
和 11,000 本未出版的书籍。
and 11,000 unpublished books.
在实践中，迁移学习应用于给定模型
In practice, transfer learning is applied on a given model
通过扔掉它的头，也就是说，
by throwing away its head, that is,
它的最后一层专注于预训练目标，
its last layers focused on the pretraining objective,
并用一个新的、随机初始化的头替换它
and replacing it with a new, randomly initialized head
适合手头的任务。
suitable for the task at hand.
例如，当我们之前微调 BERT 模型时，
For instance, when we fine-tuned a BERT model earlier,
我们删除了分类掩码词的头部
we removed the head that classified mask words
并将其替换为具有 2 个输出的分类器。
and replaced it with a classifier with 2 outputs.
因为我们的任务有两个标签。
Since our task had two labels.
为了尽可能高效，使用预训练模型
To be as efficient as possible, the pretrained model used
应该尽可能相似
should be as similar as possible
对其进行微调的任务。
to the task it's fine-tuned on.
例如，如果问题
For instance, if the problem
是对德语句子进行分类，
is to classify German sentences,
最好使用德国预训练模型。
it's best to use a German pretrained model.
但好事也有坏事。
But with the good comes the bad.
预训练模型不仅转移了它的知识，
The pretrained model does not only transfer its knowledge,
以及它可能包含的任何偏见。
but also any bias it may contain.
ImageNet 主要包含图像
ImageNet mostly contains images
来自美国和西欧。
coming from the United States and Western Europe.
所以模型用它微调
So models fine-tuned with it
通常会在来自这些国家 / 地区的图像上表现更好。
usually will perform better on images from these countries.
OpenAI 还研究了偏差
OpenAI also studied the bias
在其 GPT-3 模型的预测中
in the predictions of its GPT-3 model
这是预训练的
which was pretrained
使用猜测下一个单词目标。
using the guess the next word objective.
更改提示的性别
Changing the gender of the prompt
从他非常到她非常
from he was very to she was very
改变了大多数中性形容词的预测
changed the predictions from mostly neutral adjectives
几乎只有物理的。
to almost only physical ones.
在他们的 GPT-2 模型的模型卡中，
In their model card of the GPT-2 model,
OpenAI 也承认它的偏见
OpenAI also acknowledges its bias
并且不鼓励使用它
and discourages its use
在与人类交互的系统中。
in systems that interact with humans.
（空气呼啸）
(air whooshing)